<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Materials on Intro to R</title>
    <link>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/material/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Materials on Intro to R</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/material/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Day 3: Data Wrangling</title>
      <link>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/material/day3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/material/day3/</guid>
      <description>Slides here Data Wrangling in R On Day 1 we became familiar with R, its syntax and basic coding principles. Hopefully after completing the basic introduction, you feel more comfortable with the key concepts of R. However, don&amp;rsquo;t worry if you feel like you haven&amp;rsquo;t understood everything - this is common and perfectly normal! Learning R takes time and practice.
Today, in Session 1 we discussed what tidy and untidy data are, and why a tidy data structure is useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 2: Case Study - R for Statistics</title>
      <link>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/material/day2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/material/day2/</guid>
      <description>Slides here </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 1: R basics</title>
      <link>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/material/day1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/material/day1/</guid>
      <description>Slides here Basics of R R is a programming language designed for statistical modelling and data analysis. It is heavily supported by an active community, where new tools for data handling, visualization, and statistical analysis are constantly developed and shared.
The learning goals for today are:
become familiar with R, its syntax and basic principles know how to use R as a calculator understand and write simple R scripts perform basic operations on data be able to make simple plots First steps R is an interpreted language meaning that you can evaluate it line by line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About the Workshop</title>
      <link>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/material/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/material/about/</guid>
      <description>Who is this workshop for?
Researchers with little or no experience with R, or those who have gotten rusty and would like a refresher
Researchers with a need or interest for using R in their work
Who are your instructors?
Joy &amp;ndash; a largely self-taught but avid user of R and other programming languages. I currently use a combination of R, python, bash, and nextflow in my work
Stella &amp;ndash; a statistician with experience using S-plus (predecessor to R) and R, some python, and C++</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
