<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome! on Intro to R</title>
    <link>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome! on Intro to R</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bonus: A short intro to ggplot2</title>
      <link>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/material/bonus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/material/bonus/</guid>
      <description>On day 3 we spent time discussing the {tidyverse} - a collection of R packages that share a common design philosophy, grammar, and structure. {ggplot2} is a powerful package within the tidyverse for producing elegant graphics piece by piece.
The gg in ggplot2 means Grammar of Graphics, a graphic concept which describes plots by using a &amp;ldquo;grammar&amp;rdquo;. Similar to how sentences are composed of various parts of speech (e.g., nouns, verbs, adjectives), {ggplot2} allows us to create figures using a standard syntax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 3: Data Wrangling</title>
      <link>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/material/day3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/material/day3/</guid>
      <description>Slides here Data Wrangling in R On Day 1 we became familiar with R, its syntax and basic coding principles. Hopefully after completing the basic introduction, you feel more comfortable with the key concepts of R. However, don&amp;rsquo;t worry if you feel like you haven&amp;rsquo;t understood everything - this is common and perfectly normal! Learning R takes time and practice.
Today, in Session 1 we discussed what tidy and untidy data are, and why a tidy data structure is useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 2: Case Study - R for Statistics</title>
      <link>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/material/day2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/material/day2/</guid>
      <description>Slides here Interactive session worksheet here Interactive session data download here </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 1: R basics</title>
      <link>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/material/day1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/material/day1/</guid>
      <description>Slides here Basics of R R is a programming language designed for statistical modelling and data analysis. It is heavily supported by an active community, where new tools for data handling, visualization, and statistical analysis are constantly developed and shared.
The learning goals for today are:
become familiar with R, its syntax and basic principles know how to use R as a calculator understand and write simple R scripts perform basic operations on data be able to make simple plots First steps R is an interpreted language meaning that you can evaluate it line by line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About the Workshop</title>
      <link>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/material/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/material/about/</guid>
      <description>Who is this workshop for?
Researchers with little or no experience with R, or those who have gotten rusty and would like a refresher
Researchers with a need or interest for using R in their work
Who are your instructors?
Joy &amp;ndash; a largely self-taught but avid user of R and other programming languages. I currently use a combination of R, python, bash, and nextflow in my work
Stella &amp;ndash; a statistician with experience using S-plus (predecessor to R) and R, some python, and C++</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Additional Resources</title>
      <link>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/resources/</guid>
      <description>Interactive lessons
Posit Cloud A non-programmer friendly introduction to the R language:
Hands-On Programming with R R for excel users gitbook
Swirl: learn R interactively
tidyverse package cheatsheets
An intermediate-level exploration of data analysis using R&amp;rsquo;s tidyverse packages:
R for Data Science
R for Data Science: Exercise Solutions</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with R and RStudio on your personal machine</title>
      <link>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/install/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/install/</guid>
      <description>Please note, these instructions are for installing R/RStudio on your personal machine and do not apply to Lurie managed devices.
Security documentation When handling R and RStudio on a Lurie managed device, please refer to the following security documentation.
Security Best Practices for Using R and Rstudio in the Intro to R workshop: here
Guidance on the Use of R and RStudio: here
Install R (first) R and RStudio are two separate programs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
