<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome! on Intro to R</title>
    <link>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome! on Intro to R</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About the Workshop</title>
      <link>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/material/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/material/about/</guid>
      <description>Who is this workshop for?
Researchers with little or no experience with R, or those who have gotten rusty and would like a refresher
Researchers with a need or interest for using R in their work
Who are your instructors?
Joy &amp;ndash; a largely self-taught but avid user of R and other programming languages. I currently use a combination of R, python, bash, and nextflow in my work
Stella &amp;ndash; a statistician with experience using S-plus (predecessor to R) and R, some python, and C++</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 1: R basics</title>
      <link>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/material/day1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/material/day1/</guid>
      <description>Slides here Basics of R R is a programming language designed for statistical modelling and data analysis. It is heavily supported by an active community, where new tools for data handling, visualization, and statistical analysis are constantly developed and shared.
The learning goals for today are:
become familiar with R, its syntax and basic notions become familiar with the key functionality of the tidyverse understand and write simple R scripts be able to write documents in Rmarkdown First steps R is an interpreted language meaning that you can evaluate it line by line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Additional Resources</title>
      <link>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/resources/</guid>
      <description> Interactive lessons
Posit Cloud A non-programmer friendly introduction to the R language:
Hands-On Programming with R An intermediate-level exploration of data analysis using R&amp;rsquo;s tidyverse packages:
R for Data Science
R for Data Science: Exercise Solutions
Swirl: learn R interactively
An introduction to manipulating and visualizing data in R using the tidyverse suite of packages
RBootcamp · by Ted Laderas and Jessica Minnier </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with R and RStudio on your own machine</title>
      <link>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/install/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luriechildrensbioinformatics.github.io/introR/install/</guid>
      <description>Install R (first) R and RStudio are two separate programs. You must install R first, then install RStudio desktop
Windows &amp;ndash; download from: https://cran.rstudio.com/bin/windows/base/
Mac OS &amp;ndash; download the latest .pkg file from: https://cran.rstudio.com/bin/macosx/ (top link)
Install RStudio (second) Select the RStudio desktop download file corresponding to your operating system from: https://posit.co/download/rstudio-desktop/#download Open RStudio Open RStudio by clicking on the RStudio icon (round blue circle with an R in the center).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
